<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>A short account of Blurton-Spaw-Water, with some plain directions, and necessary rules for the more efficacious drinking of it.</title>
            <author>Westmacott, William.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1694</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 16 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 3 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2014-11">2014-11 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B31639</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing W1421A</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Interim Tract Supplement Guide 778.k.15.[5]</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R231538</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99888683</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">ocm99888683</idno>
            <idno type="VID">203963</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B31639)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 203963)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books; Tract supplement ; E7:2[5])</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>A short account of Blurton-Spaw-Water, with some plain directions, and necessary rules for the more efficacious drinking of it.</title>
                  <author>Westmacott, William.</author>
                  <author>Floyer, John, Sir, 1649-1734.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>4 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed for William Bateman, apothecary in Stone, in Stafford-shire, who is intrusted to take any observations from any ingenious or distemper'd persons, that make trials of this spaw.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London: :</pubPlace>
                  <date>[1694]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Imprint from colophon.</note>
                  <note>Dated and signed at end: New-Castle-under-line, Mar.30.1694 ... Will. Westmacott.</note>
                  <note>Also at end: [recommendation given ] signed: John Floyer.; dated: Litchfield, Feb.16.93.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Mineral waters --  Therapeutic use --  England --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Medicine --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2013-11</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-12</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-02</date>
            <label>Anne Simpson</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-02</date>
            <label>Anne Simpson</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-03</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="account">
            <pb facs="tcp:203963:1"/>
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:203963:1"/>
            <head>A Short Account of <hi>Blurton-Spaw-Water,</hi> with ſome plain Directions, and neceſſary Rules for the more efficacious Drink<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing of it.</head>
            <p>
               <seg rend="decorInit">T</seg>HIS Paper being chiefly deſigned for the meaneſt Readers, I ſhall de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liver my ſelf in as few, and plain words, as the ſubject Matter will al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>low, hoping by ſeveral more Experiments made, and obſerved of this <hi>Mineral Water,</hi> hereafter by others, as well as my ſelf, that Learned and Inquiſitive Perſons, (or any others that diſlike this <hi>Propter Autho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rem</hi>) may receive a more large and ſuitable Satisfaction in deeper Notions, from ſome other more Learn'd and Philoſophical Pen: And in the mean time, theſe plain Directions have been deſir'd by ſome, and perhaps may be ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceptable, and uſeful to moſt ſorts of Perſons, that flock to this <hi>Spaw;</hi> therefore not regarding the Cenfures of the <hi>Momy's,</hi> obſerving Method, the better to be un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>derſtood, I ſhall,</p>
            <p>Firſt tell you from what Minerals, (as learned Phyſicians, and other Philophical Men do affirm) this <hi>Water</hi> doth receive its Medicinal Virtues. Secondly, I ſhall endeavour to anſwer an Objection thrown abroad againſt it. Thirdly, I ſhall tell you its Virtues, and in what Diſtempers it hath done, and in all probability it may do good. Fourthly, You ſhall have the beſt Method and Manner how to drink it, without any Prejudice to your Bodies.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Firſt,</hi> The <hi>Minerals</hi> (upon Trials and Experiments) which are very ſtrong in this <hi>Water,</hi> are <hi>Sulphur Flowers,</hi> and <hi>Iron Other,</hi> which unite into an imperfect <hi>Vitriol</hi> in the <hi>Water,</hi> that is (more plainly) chiefly <hi>Steel,</hi> ſome <hi>Sulphur,</hi> and a little <hi>Copper</hi> inter<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mixt; which two laſt gives the Vomiting and Purging quality, this <hi>Water</hi> is ſo ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cellently endued with, and from the <hi>Iron</hi> and <hi>Steel</hi> it works ſo ſtrongly by Urine. Now, to illuſtrate this (for the ſatisfaction of the Inquiſitive and Learned) not on<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly have I tried, and often found it (and many others) to turn with a few Grains of <hi>Gills</hi> into a deep Purple colour at the <hi>Well,</hi> and at my own Houſe; but alſo it turn<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed ſo at <hi>Litchfield</hi> after their Carriage, and Keeping many days; ſome Bottles being ſent to the Learned Sir <hi>John Floyer,</hi> Knt. and Doctor of Phyſick, who cauſed others, beſides himſelf, to drink of it there; and by ſtanding ſometime in a Glaſs, a bleuiſh Skin appears on the top of the <hi>Water,</hi> and hence ſaith Sir <hi>John</hi> (in his Letters to me) we may conclude, that this <hi>Water</hi> hath the ſame <hi>Minerals,</hi> as the common <hi>Chalybeate Waters</hi> have.</p>
            <p>But m<gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>reover there is this ſingular in this <hi>Water,</hi> from all others that are <hi>Chaly<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>beate,</hi> that by Spirit of Harts-Horn dropt into it (at <hi>Litchfield,</hi> and many other pla<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ces) it precipitated green Clouds and Sediment, (very pleaſant to the Beholders) and not of an yellow <hi>Other</hi> colour, as other <hi>Chalybeate Waters</hi> do, neither will it turn green with <hi>Syrup of Violets,</hi> as other <hi>Chalybeate Waters</hi> uſe to do, but gives a green <hi>Tincture</hi> to old <hi>ruſty Iron</hi> put into it; by which Experiments, and alſo by its Purging Faculty, it is believed that ſomething of <hi>Copper</hi> is contained in the <hi>Pyrites,</hi> or <hi>Fire-ſtone,</hi> which furniſh the <hi>Water,</hi> with its ſtrong <hi>Chalybeate</hi> taſte, from the <hi>Sulphur</hi> and <hi>Iron Ocher</hi> all <hi>Pyrites</hi> contain. Upon theſe Experiments 'tis adjudged to be ſtronger than the <hi>Waters</hi> of <hi>Quarne, Bromiſh, Poles worth,</hi> or <hi>Aſtrop;</hi> nay, ſome Learned Men at the <hi>Well</hi> have affirmed it ſtronger than <hi>Tunbridge,</hi> and may be compared with <hi>Scarborough Spaw,</hi> which purges as this doth, and therefore muſt needs have greater Succeſs, than moſt other <hi>Steel Waters</hi> in <hi>England.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>Secondly,</hi> The Objection is, 'tis a <hi>Coal pit-water,</hi> dreining dry thro' a Slough or
<pb n="2" facs="tcp:203963:2"/>Gutter, ſome <hi>Coal-pits,</hi> as well as the <hi>Iron Stone pits,</hi> on <hi>Meer Heath,</hi> therefore un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wholſome.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Anſw.</hi> The ſame Objection is made againſt the <hi>Waters</hi> of <hi>Polsworth</hi> and <hi>Bromich,</hi> which are near <hi>Coal-pits</hi> alſo, and yet experience has proved them, (as ſaith Sir <hi>John</hi> in a late Letter to me) both to be uſeful and innocent: It is the <hi>Pyrites,</hi> or <hi>Fire-Stone,</hi> (found in Beds, in getting of <hi>Coal</hi> or <hi>Iron-ſtone,</hi> thro' which the <hi>Water</hi> runs) gives the <hi>Chalybeate Tincture</hi> to the <hi>Water;</hi> for if a little <hi>Pyrites</hi> be put into a Glaſs of fair Water, in a few Minutes (as often as it hath been tried) it gives a Steel taſte to the <hi>Water,</hi> and by adding Galls to the ſame Glaſs, it turns of a deep Purple in a ſmall time. Moreover, <hi>Chalybeat Springs</hi> lie ſhallow, and are often ſpoiled by digging into, and therefore come not from the <hi>Coal</hi> which lie deep, and the <hi>Fire-ſtone</hi> which gives the <hi>Chalybeat</hi> Virtue) lies very much above the <hi>Coal,</hi> as Miners inform us; furthermore, neither <hi>Iron-ſtone</hi> nor <hi>Coal</hi> can be diſſolved in Water; the laſt be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing a Sulphurous Oily <hi>Bitumen,</hi> cannot mix with Water no more than Oyl can; and being no Sulphurous ſtinking ſmell is found in <hi>Water,</hi> it is plainly evident it hath no ill quality from the <hi>Coals:</hi> Beſide there is no ſuch noxious quality in Coal (as the Objectors imagine) as appears by warming Drink with a red hot Coal, as many Country-men uſe to do, and others light their Tobacco with it, without pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>judice, and eaſily taſt the Sulphurous Acid in it, and believe its good for the Lungs; and this ſure is ſufficient to ſatifie any Timerous (if Rational) Perſon.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Thirdly,</hi> I deſign not to erect a Creature of my own, by extolling the Virtues of this <hi>Water,</hi> ſo as to be accounted the Author of their Fame; but ſeeing it is a ſtron<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ger <hi>Steel-water,</hi> I ſhall, for the Benefit of our Country, ſet down a Catalogue of ſome Diſtempers, for which you may expect Remedy by the uſe of it.</p>
            <p>It is a very clear <hi>Water,</hi> and that is a peculiar Advantage to it; It hath to my knowledge cured the <hi>Green-Sickneſs</hi> in ſeveral Virgins, brought away <hi>Worms</hi> from Children, <hi>Gravel</hi> and <hi>Stones</hi> from many Men, and helped <hi>Piſſing of Blood,</hi> bravely helped a Gentlewoman of great Quality of an ill Habit of Body, with Hyſterical Maladies: Another good Gentlewoman (under my care) of a hot ſplenetical Habit of Body, and Hectical in the firſt degree; greatly efficatious in the <hi>Scurvy,</hi> as Mr. <hi>Atherly,</hi> Mr. <hi>Barber,</hi> and others can teſtifie; it procured to all that drank it regularly, a good Appetite, and amended the Colour in Womens Faces, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>By this it appears to be a great <hi>Opener of Obſtructions,</hi> the cauſes of moſt Diſeaſes. It purges the <hi>Bowels</hi> by ſiege, the <hi>Meſentery, Liver, Reins, &amp;c.</hi> by Urine, carrying off, deſtroying and ſweetening any <hi>Corroſive, Soure,</hi> and <hi>Scorbutick Salts in the Blood,</hi> thereby cleanſing and purifying the ſame: With ſome it purged ſo much, as if it would leave nothing to paſs by Urine; and yet paſſed ſo plentifully by Urine, as if it found no vent by Stool, ſcarce ever failing of purging (except in exceeding con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtipated Bodies, and in ſuch as drank but two or three Pints for Pleaſure or Compa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny) turning the Excrements of all into a ſad Green, or Blackiſh colour, as all <hi>Steel-waters</hi> and Medicines do: It Vomits alſo, as I obſerved in many, beſides my ſelf, who often drank it for trials ſake.</p>
            <p>To be poſitive in its Virtues till more Experimental Hiſtories have given the Country ſatisfaction, were to extenuate the reality of the Premiſſes; but from its Mineral Principles, it juſtly may be recommended to be uſed in the hot <hi>Scurvies, Jaundice, Incipient Dropſies.</hi> Hectical and Hyſterical caſes, the <hi>VVhite Flux,</hi> and <hi>Bleedings at the Noſe;</hi> in Diſeaſes of the <hi>Breaſt</hi> or <hi>Lungs,</hi> that need or can admit Purgation; in <hi>Vomitings, decayed Appetites,</hi> and <hi>Indigeſtion;</hi> in Diſeaſes of the <hi>Head,</hi> as <hi>Convulſive caſes, Falling-Sickneſs, &amp;c.</hi> and in Nervous Caſes, as <hi>Tremblings, Pal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſies, old Rheumatiſms, Palpitation of the Heart, Flatus, Hypochondriack Melancholy,</hi> and <hi>Cholicks</hi> ariſing from a hot cauſe: In old <hi>Gonorrhea's</hi> and <hi>Claps</hi> ill cur'd, <hi>
                  <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>lcers of the Kidnies or Bladder, Diabetes, Strangury, Sharpneſs of VVater:</hi> Outwardly it
<pb n="3" facs="tcp:203963:2"/>muſt needs be good in all <hi>
                  <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>lcers, Sore Eyes, Scorbutick running Sores, VVild-fires, Ring worms, Kings-Evil, Scabs, Itch, Cankers,</hi> and in <hi>Scorbutick Sores of the Mouth</hi> and <hi>Gumms.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>Fourthly,</hi> Tho' thoſe that are in perfect Health, (that come for pleaſure) may drink it without any hurt to their Bodies, yet it may harm ſuch as are ſickly, if not uſed aright; and it's impoſſible to direct ſo, as to anſwer every Man's particular caſe: But a preparation of the Body, by purging, may be neceſſary, and ſafe in moſt Maladies, to make way for the Water: And bleeding ſome few days before (or after) drinking, eſpecially in Plethorical Bodies, or hot Maladies, may be ve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry profitable; for by it, Obſtructions will ſooner yield to the Water: And purg<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing once in ten or fourteen days (as I did ſome Patients the laſt Summer) may be proper in ſome caſes, as may the taking ſome Alteratives, and appropriated Medi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cines, relating to the part Affected, or to the Nature or Complication of the Sick<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs. Therefore, underſtanding Perſons that have diſtemper'd Bodies, do uſually at <hi>Spaws,</hi> conſult ſome Phyſician, whether the <hi>Water</hi> be proper or not for their Condition, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> whereas in others, leſs diſcreet, and unadviſedly drinking of it, it may not do that good (but perhaps harm) as by a regular Method.</p>
            <p>Begin at ſix or ſeven a Clock in the Morning with two half pint Glaſſes (walk<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing two or three Minutes betwixt them) then walk gently a quarter of an Hour, or ſomething more, then take two more Glaſſes, and your Walk as before, ſo re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>peat your Glaſſes the firſt Morning with your Walks, till you have taken eight or nine Glaſſes at moſt, and ſo walk or ride gently, till the Water is paſſed off, which may be in two or three hours time, after the laſt Glaſs, that is by twelve or one of the Clock.</p>
            <p>The days following increaſe your quantity, by one or two Glaſſes each Morn<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, till you come to 12, 14, or 16 Glaſſes (which will be ſix, ſeven, or eight pints) as you are adviſed too, or as it paſſes off, and you can bear it: And after you are come up to the juſt number of Glaſſes you intend, you may hold to that number every Morning a week, or more days, if your caſe require it, or you may decreaſe, daily abating one Glaſs, till you come to the number you begun with, or rather under, and ſo leave off; taking a Purge after it, as may be proper in ſome, tho' not in all Caſes and Bodies.</p>
            <p>Remember not to walk too faſt thither, nor drink too faſt, nor walk too faſt home again after it, ſo as to heat or ſweat; for thereby the <hi>Water</hi> is forc'd into the Habit of the Body, and hinders its working off thro' the Bowels; and this is one great cauſe of ſuch <hi>Itchings, Pimples,</hi> and <hi>Breakings-forth,</hi> as many the laſt Summers com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plained off.</p>
            <p>If the Stomach chill at them, and grow nauſeous, a bit of a <hi>Stomachical Lozenge, Candid-Orange, Lemmon-Peel, Mint-Cake,</hi> or a few <hi>Carraway Comfits</hi> may be chew'd now and then, but the leſs the better: And if any have ſuch weak Stomachs they cannot faſt till Dinner, at twelve or one of the Clock, a Meſs of warm Broth or Gruel will be exceeding proper for them at ten or eleven. Shun Salt and Fry'd Meat, Sallets, Cheeſe, exerciſe gently after Dinner; ſleep not, nor drink hard, but remember Temperance in all things.</p>
            <p>As to the time of the year to drink, 'tis uſually from mid-May, till the end of <hi>Au<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>guſt;</hi> the hotter, and drier the Seaſon is the better. A fortnights time to drink them regularly may be the ſhorteſt, ſome Bodies and Diſtempers may require three Weeks, others a Month or more; Mr. <hi>Barber</hi> drank it ſix Weeks compleat in the two laſt Summers.</p>
            <p>This <hi>Water,</hi> as many can teſtifie, has been carried ſix, ten, and many more Miles in Bottles, kept three or four days, drank, and work'd off very well, and ſo fetch'd freſh every third or fourth day for three weeks together; enquire of <hi>John Licet,</hi>
               <pb n="4" facs="tcp:203963:3"/>of <hi>Hopton,</hi> who drank it older than ever I yet heard of with great Succeſs; but <hi>purius ex ipſo fonte bibuntur Aquae:</hi> 'Tis moſt efficatious no doubt when drank at the Well.</p>
            <p>To conclude (Brevity having been my aim) I hope if any meet with help by the uſe of this <hi>Water,</hi> they will be ſo gratefully Ingenious to it, as to confeſs it to me, or ſome other Phyſician or Friend, ſo that the Virtues of it may be grounded on Matter of Fact and Obſervations: And if the poorer ſort of People that come to this <hi>Spaw,</hi> where <hi>(Deo volente)</hi> I often ſhall be, require my Advice, I ſhall be ready to give it them <hi>Gratis,</hi> as I am bound in Conſcience to do, and that as carefully, as to any other of our Country, to whom I am</p>
            <closer>
               <dateline>
                  <hi>New-Caſtle-under-line,</hi> 
                  <date>Mar. 30. 1694.</date>
               </dateline>
               <signed>
                  <hi>A Friend and Servant,</hi> Will. Weſtmacott.</signed>
            </closer>
         </div>
         <div type="endorsement">
            <opener>
               <salute>SIR,</salute>
            </opener>
            <p>I Freely give my Recommendation of <hi>Blurton-Water</hi> to all my Country-men for the Curing thoſe Diſtempers mention'd in your Paper, ſo that they fitly pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pare themſelves before Drinking by proper Phyſick, and follow your Directions in your Paper, while they perſue the courſe of drinking the <hi>Water;</hi> and I queſti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on not, but your publiſhing your Account of theſe <hi>Waters,</hi> will be very uſeful, for the making them more known to all our Patients in our Country, and thoſe of our Profeſſion will give you their thanks, for the communicating the Trials and Experiments you have made about them, for which I ſhall upon all oc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>caſions return you mine, who am,</p>
            <closer>
               <dateline>
                  <hi>Litchfield,</hi> 
                  <date>Feb. 16. 93.</date>
               </dateline>
               <salute>SIR, </salute>
               <signed>
                  <hi>Your Faithful, and Humble Servant,</hi> John Floyer.</signed>
            </closer>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>
               <hi>London:</hi> Printed for <hi>William Bateman,</hi> Apothecary in <hi>Stone,</hi> in <hi>Staf<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ford-ſhire,</hi> who is intruſted to take any Obſervations from any Inge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nious or Diſtemper'd Perſons, that make Trials of this <hi>Spaw.</hi>
            </p>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
